Full stack engineer with a passion for front end web development. With experience in Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux and a background as a strong editorial design professional, I bring a creative lens to each project. Adept at prioritizing key deliverables under tight deadlines and collaborate effectively across departments.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Come on Kayak | Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

an app for kayakers to make comments on past trips and create upcoming ones

- Persists data to a Rails database and provides a Rails API
- Displays a React, Redux frontend with Semantic-ui-React
- Fetches data from the Rails API using Javascript

Adopt a Pet | Github Frontend | Github Backend | Demo

an app for adopting/maintaining a virtual pet without the upkeep of a live one

- Persists each user's pets and experience to a Postgres database and provides a Rails API with JWT authorization
- Displays a React frontend with Semantic-ui-React and CSS
- Employs flexbox with hamburger menu

Abode Haven | Github | Demo

an app for building management admin and apt seekers based in nyc

- Built with Ruby on Rails, Postgres, Bootstrap and CSS with endpoints for Users, Bldgs and Apts
- Implements Devise to allow Admin to sign in and use features specific to Admin

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Adobe Creative Cloud | CSS | HTML | JavaScript | React | Redux | Ruby on Rails

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Various Clients ranging from Publications to Individuals

Freelance Web Developer | August 2019-Present

Freelance Print, Digital Art Director | June 2017-Present

Hearst | Women's Health | Prevention | People Magazine all located in New York, NY

Digital Art Director | September 2011-May 2017

- Reviewed content from print material and translated it using elements of company's designated brand for user interaction on ipad/iphone
- Utilized Edge Animate and Photoshop to produce engaging interactive material for the reader
- Redesigned ipad/iphone editions to reflect current format to insure continued viewing by subscribers
- Directed staff of 4, troubleshot design decisions to improve layout to best captivate and maintain readers' attention

Shape Magazine | Time Inc. Custom Publishing | TV Guide | Worth Magazine all located in New York. NY

Art Director | April 1996-August 2011

- Produced effective layouts, contributed to multiple redesigns under high pressure environment; met deadlines on or ahead of schedule while continuously updating content based on feedback
- Collaborated with editors to visualize their perception of stories; independently created end products
- Conceptualized story content with illustrators to determine visual representation; hired talent based on whether subject matter and illustrator/photographer specialization were aligned
- Awarded for outstanding design by:
 Print's Best Typography, PRINT'S Regional Design Annual, The Society of Publication Design

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY | Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript immersive program

 $\textbf{General Assembly, New York, NY} \hspace{0.1in} \textbf{|} \hspace{0.1in} \textbf{Front-end web development}$

New School University , New York, NY | Non matriculated coursework on HTML, web design

New York University, New York, NY | Dreamweaver coursework

Kansas University, Lawrence, KS | Bachelor of Fine Arts in Visual Communications

